<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prematurely optimizing (Posty o fusion)</title><link>https://stanczakdominik.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/categories/fusion.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>pl</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="https://matrix.to/#/@StanczakDominik:matrix.org"&gt;Dominik Stańczak-Marikin&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
src="/images/creativecommons.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 15:16:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A pandemic story, or, what I learned working with nuclear fusion</title><link>https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/ipplm-post-mortem/</link><dc:creator>Dominik Stańczak-Marikin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As promised, here's a post on the story of my time at &lt;a href="https://www.ifpilm.pl/"&gt;IPPLM - the Institute of Plasma Physics and Laser Microfusion&lt;/a&gt;, where I worked for the last almost-three-years. Past tense, because since September I've successfully found remote work as a Python software developer at a large pharmaceutical company. Speaking of... I don't think I can say as much as I'd hoped about the projects we're working on, but, suffice to say, I think they have some real potential for helping people with neurodegenerative diseases. So I'm still trying to tackle one of the Large Problems, just... another one, and more so from a backend/support angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing this, I realized that this story was also deeply intertwined with the story of the global COVID-19 pandemic, because that turned the whole situation on its head. I thought about separating the two, but decided instead to embrace it and tell it whole rather than in pieces. So, beware, this is going to get &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt;. To alleviate that, I've broken it up more than usual and have placed the major takeaways in specifically formatted sections throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that disclaimer in place... onto the story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/ipplm-post-mortem/" class="btn btn-outline-secondary"&gt;Czytaj więcej…&lt;/a&gt; (zostało 12 minut czytania)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/ipplm-post-mortem/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fusion 1/4: Nuclear power as of 2021</title><link>https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/fusion1/</link><dc:creator>Dominik Stańczak-Marikin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi! In the new year, &lt;a href="https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/fusion1/2021"&gt;as promised&lt;/a&gt;, you'll see more actual science discussions on this page. I have - I think, for the first time since I started writing here - a plan for the next four posts. The first will discuss nuclear power and its place in the world. The second will tell you a little about its most interesting future alternative - fusion power. Next up, we'll discuss its history a little and where I predict it'll head in the near future; and in the fourth, I'll try to discuss a little about what we're actually doing with it in terms of research work. I can't wait to get to the fourth part, so that should be at least motivating. Let's get to it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/fusion1/" class="btn btn-outline-secondary"&gt;Czytaj więcej…&lt;/a&gt; (zostało 7 minut czytania)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://stanczakdominik.github.io/pl/posts/fusion1/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>